[music]
>> All right, good to see everybody. I'm
real excited to welcome back Dalton
Risner back in the fold, reintroduce
him. Um, you know, Dalton is a is a
critical part of our team, critical part
of our offensive line. A guy that showed
up
a week before the season started, before
the first game. Yep. Uh, played over
half of that game and continued to play
at a high level all season for us. It
gave us a ton of confidence um in our
offensive line playing. So, Dalton's
just got uh not only has a high talent
level, but a wealth of experience.
Brings a lot of veteran leadership to
our team and our offense. And we're
we're really happy to have him and his
wife Whitney back in the fold. And happy
to welcome another Big 8 alum uh back
into the building. Dalton Risner. I wish
to take it from here. All right,
appreciate you, coach. Thank you.
Stoked to be here, guys.
What was this What was this process like
for you this time around? Good to see
you, bro. Appreciate all your belief all
year, all the really great things you
said about me, man. It really means a
lot to me, bro. So, really good to see
you again.
Um also really grateful for my head
coach here. A big reason why I wanted to
come back to Cincinnati is because of
Zac Taylor. Um
and I'm probably going to say a lot
today that has nothing to do with the
questions that you asked, but I just
feel like I'm full of gratitude um
coming back and being with Scott Peters.
Just got to give Orlando Brown a hug.
Was on the phone last night with Mims.
I've talked to Ted. I've talked to Joe.
Um just so many people
including the fan base, including all of
you guys, the city
the restaurant Jeff Ruby's. I mean, I
could go on and on about every reason
why I wanted to come back and how you
guys have welcomed me and my wife with
open arms, but
um we've known about this deal for like
the last 48 hours and it's been one of
like the hardest secrets to keep ever.
So, um my little Adam Schefter back
there got to break the news this
morning, which I thought was pretty
exciting. As you get let later in your
career, I feel like you try to have some
fun with this cuz you never know when
it's going to be the last year. So,
um yeah, I'm just super overwhelmed,
man, with gratitude and thankfulness to
come back here, especially with
the ups and downs of last season. And I
think I just answered everything but
your question. What did you ask me? No,
it's all right. I have a lot on my mind.
>> [laughter]
>> How How much How much What was this
process like this time around? I know
you had to get the deal done early and
stuff. Like how much was that a factor
in all this? I think it was a huge
factor, truth be told. And I think I'm I
can say this because it's
after the season, I told everyone this
is where I wanted to be. So, when it
came to this process, of course, it did
take a little bit of time. The Bengals
and myself, I think, were proactive in
getting this deal done ever since the
season ended. But it got to a point for
me where I started putting pressure on
my agent. I got one of the best agents
in the world in Drew Rosenhaus, but I I
truly did mean what I said. I didn't
really care to hit free agency and see
if someone wanted to sign me to a two or
three-year deal or maybe pay me more
cash per year. I wanted to be a
Cincinnati Bengal. And it got to a point
where we were so close in terms that it
was time to get a deal done. So, the
Bengals um did a lot of compromising and
I did a lot of compromising and we came
uh to a middle point into a middle
ground to sign the deal and I was so
thankful for that. I got to give Duke
Tobin a hug today, uh Mike Brown, uh
Katie. I mean, on and on, Steven. So
many people upstairs that I'm thankful
for, but this process was just so much
different because I've never felt this
way about an organization. I've never
truly just wanted to be back and not
even test my market. And I'm at the
point in my career where this is where
I'm going to be my best with Scott
Peters and Joe Burrow and Ted Karras and
Amarius Mims. And I didn't really care
about the logistic side of it. This is
where I want to be. What was it about
this offensive line room that just fit
you? Like you guys seem to have such
great chemistry together. What is it
that why you came in and it was such a
good connection?
>> Yeah, it's a great question. I truly
feel like I've never been seen or valued
like I have here. And I think that that
started in the offensive line room and
that started with Ted Karras. Ted Karras
is Cincinnati Bengals through and
through.
Um I You know what's crazy? I've never
been a guy to look up to very many
people and then I've truly always just
said like Jesus is like the only person
I've ever like truly looked up to, but I
look up to Ted in a lot of ways. And I
remember after my very first game, he
had like this crazy quote that he gave
to Dan. And I even loved it so much I
had Dan send it to me and it's saved in
my phone. It was talking about I don't
know. Dan, do you remember it?
Yeah, it was uh the most
greatest example of professionalism he
had ever witnessed. ever displayed. And
you guys know Ted, he really fluffed it
up. It was great. But like [laughter] I
just think to your question that Ted
opened the door and put his arms wide
open and said like like we take you as
you are and it just it made it to where
I could just come in here and be exactly
who I was. And then Orlando Brown, I
think, was getting interviewed by one of
you and someone asked him about me and
he just said, "Oh, this guy's a dog.
Like we need him. He's going to help us
win games." And I didn't even I've never
met I've never talked to these guys. And
they're speaking so highly of me and
they're the centerfolds of this football
team. And I don't know what I did to
deserve that, but really grateful that
they did. And I think that because of
the way they opened their arms and
accepted me, allowed me to come in here
and just focus on being exactly who I
was. When do you think you hit your
stride with the offensive line?
Well, certainly wasn't after the
Jacksonville game. Um that's for sure.
Um it was an up and down year and I say
that
being okay to say it because that's just
that's just part of life. Life isn't
easy and you know, I was benched this
last year. That was the first time in my
whole career I was benched and I think
you have two choices in that moment and
you have to decide, okay,
who who am I going to be in these
moments? And I think once I decided like
I'm still so grateful to be here. I want
to be an example to my future kids. I
still have a lot of football left that I
know I can play. And I think coming back
and when I got that first start at left
guard against the Green Bay Packers. And
then I started at left guard against the
Pittsburgh Steelers at home on Thursday
night. And those two starts at left
guard, that's kind of the position I'm
used to. That's the position I've always
played in my career other than this last
two years. Um kind of kick-started me
and got me back to being who Dalton
Risner was. And I think part of that was
having six days to prepare for the
Browns after showing up here signing
late. But after starting at left guard
those two games and when I got my first
start back at right guard,
I keep trying to remember who it was. I
got in against the Pittsburgh Steelers
away on the road.
Regardless, that middle point of the
year when I got back to right guard is
when I felt like things really just
started going really really good for me.
I felt like I was good in the offensive
line room. I was getting to know Scott
Peters and the way that he coaches and I
knew people in the building and I knew
how to get around, to say the least. I
was settled in my house at home. And I
think as the year went on, it just
continued to get better and better. I
was going to say is that when you kind
of realized this is really comfortable,
great quarterback
uh of the future, this is kind of where
I want to be. Yeah, it is. I think the
center point of the season leading to
the back half, especially when Joe got
back and playing with Flacco as well. I
mean, there were so many different keys
to it, but as each week went on, I just
kept seeing it more and more for like,
wow, this is where I think I can be
great. Scott Peters is going to make me
a two times better football player. This
guy he knows me. He understands me. He
gets me. He values me for what I bring
to the table. Wow, Zac Taylor sees me.
Oh, Dan Pitcher just called me out in
front of the whole team for hustling
downfield and picking up my teammates.
I've been doing that for eight years and
I've never had another coach call me out
in a meeting for it. I'm like, wow, like
this place sees me. They value me. The
fan base is
talking about how much they want me here
and how much they love me and Burrow's
advocating for me and Mims is now
tweeting about me being back being He's
lying talking about me being the best
right guard in the league, but
regardless, like so many people are
backing me and I'm like, yeah, I think
it just every week I was surprised with
how much I was more and more saying this
is where I need to be. Going back to Ted
and the line and how they've embraced
you, what have they been like throughout
the past a month or so as you guys have
been through this negotiating process
trying to get you back and what did you
hear from them? Yeah, [clears throat]
they've been they've been so great. You
know, it's one thing for people to tell
you something at the end of the year and
say, "Hey, you know, we want you back.
We would love to have you back. We love
you for who you are." But then not
really hear from them. But I heard from
so many people just asking me how things
were going and Burrow was hitting me up
a a lot just checking in on the process.
And that meant a lot to me because he
valued the offensive lineman that I was
and he wanted to bring me back. So, I
can't wait to get to work for him and
protect him this season. Um but guys
like Ted would continuously check in.
Scott Peters, Mike McCarthy, Justin
Moscati. I mean, there's so many people
a part of this that really wanted me
here. That was really cool to see them
not only tell me at the end of the year,
but continuously check in and kind of
check how this process was going. What's
What What's What's the amount of time
you had from when you were last playing
for the Vikings until you signed here in
August? Was that Was that time for you
maybe motivating that you feel like it
it helped you play your best now than it
got you another contract? Like how did
that time fuel you and do you feel like
it
factored into how you played last season
ultimately giving you this opportunity?
That's such a good question. I love that
you asked that because for the last
three years of my career, I've done all
my training on by myself pretty much.
Like my first four years with the Denver
Broncos, I trained at the Denver Bronco
facility  Loren Landow's
facility, who was the strength coach for
the Broncos. But once I left and I
started this free agency process,
I had my own regimen. I've always taken
a lot of pride in that and the foods
that I eat, the way that I condition,
the workouts that I do. So, there's been
some long off-season, but let's just
talk about the one that you are talking
about. I finished my season with the
Minnesota Vikings in a playoff game. We
played at Arizona Cardinals stadium
against the LA Rams. And that whole
off-season, I think, from that day that
I got done to when the Cincinnati
Bengals picked me up was almost seven
months. And that whole seven months, I
never once was in a gym with a trainer.
It was me every single time. I can't
tell you guys how many times I woke up
at 6:00 in the morning and went and did
the same routine monotonous workout in
my home gym and did that for an hour and
a half, grabbed the same pair of cleats,
walked down my little community, you
guys can look up this community,
Parrish, Florida,
and I [clears throat] get to this little
piece of grass. There's only one piece
of grass that I can walk to and it's
right in front of the mailboxes and it's
where all the We're in a retirement
community. It's where all they take
their dogs to go poop. So, it's 6:30 in
the morning, 7:00 in the morning. I'm
not lying, guys. I'm walking every day
and I ask myself the question of why am
I doing this?
Like the NFL doesn't want me every year.
Free agency doesn't go my way. Every
year I find a way to start and play.
I've started over 93 games in the NFL
and every year I can't get a team to
take a shot on me in a in a in a
multi-year deal or whatever it is,
right? So, there's so many questions
every time walking to that field of
like, should I even do this anymore?
Like should I even Why am I waking up at
6:00 a.m. and lifting? No one cares. You
know what I mean? Like how who am I
going to prove this to? What am I trying
to do? And I'm so glad I continued to do
that. Sometimes I felt like it was just
me, my wife, and Jesus and then my pair
of cleats. But, I mentioned the piece of
grass because it's uneven ground and
it's not an ideal place to be training
and I know I could go train in a gym,
but it's just where I found myself to be
best and there was this one day
apart from everyone stopping and just
kind of looking at you like, what is
this grown 31-year-old bald guy doing on
this piece of grass with his cleats?
This guy walks by and he's like, "Hell
of a fantasy football league you're in,
huh?" And it was like funny, but also
like devastating because I'm like like
funny because I'm actually training to
be in the NFL and I'm an NFL football
player, but sad because I'm like like I
don't blame him for thinking this. Um
but, it's so cool to think back to all
that work and all that work that I did
like it paid off like cuz when I showed
up here, I thought I was going to have
three or four weeks before I was really
going to be put in the fold, but there
was an injury, they counted on me. So
thankful I was in my playbook, but
really like I was mentally and
physically ready because of all the work
that I did and I never once
gave up or skipped a day and said like,
"Hey, this isn't this isn't going to be
what I'm going to do. I know I'm going
to play." And that's the reason I was
able to go into the dog pound and play
for the Cincinnati Bengals. And then to
be sitting here today after so many
people said, "Hey, once you take a
league minimum deal, you're kind of
you're kind of tied there. You're not
going to be able to really sign a deal
that's bigger. It's not going to
happen." So, that's why I feel like I'm
filled with so much gratitude and
thankfulness is because of that long off
season and how hard it was every single
day to to get up and work whenever
everyone else said, "I
kind of written off Dalton Risner. He's
not going to play this year." And then
after I take a league minimum deal and
don't really play good against the
Jacksonville Jaguars and kind of lose my
job, you're written off even more. And
you and you have choices in those times
to decide to keep moving forward or not
and I think that's what makes today so
special. What what enables you to bite
down then on the back end of the year to
kind of show people, "Hey, I can do this
and I can't play in this league?"
Everything I've been through, my whole
story
dating back to
my parents having nothing growing up and
us getting Christmas presents dropped
off on our doorstep, something I didn't
go through, right? Something I don't
even remember, but that's what my
family's about. That's who the Risner
family is is I feel like we know how to
work and in times where it gets really
tough, you either bite down on your
mouthpiece or you spit it out. And
I bit down on my mouthpiece this year
because that's just what I'm made up of.
And this ain't the first trial that I've
been through. I've been counted out
before. Came from a Wiggins High School,
town of 800 people, 16 guys on my
football team, no one wanted to give me
a Division I scholarship. So, I've been
here, bro, and I'm not going to bore you
with my whole football story, but it's
it's nothing new. And this year will
bring its own trial. I don't even know
what it I hope I don't I don't know what
it's going to be or what it'll be, but
there'll be hard times and I'll bite
down on my mouthpiece every single time.
And that doesn't mean it'll always work
out for you. But, um I also bite down on
it because it's the NFL. I get to go
block for Joe Burrow, block next to Ted
Karras, and uh have an NFL football team
employ me. Dalton Risner, the kid from
Wiggins, Colorado, no one believed in.
I'll always have a reason to bite down
on my mouthpiece. And the day that I
don't is uh the day I need to be done.
The day that I don't That'll That'll
never come though. You mentioned the the
Jacksonville game a couple times. The
day after that, you were really raw,
really honest about missing a block with
that got Joe hurt.
>> Yeah. Wondering how long did that stick
with you? Did you flush it or did it
motivate you the rest of the season? Was
it something you kept continued to think
about?
>> I'll always remember it. I'm never going
to forget about it, but I flushed it for
sure. And I've always been a guy that's
going to be real. Let's just call it for
what it is, man. We live in a world
where we all try to be perfect and we
all try to have it all put together all
the time and no one wants to admit their
mistakes and
I'm going to I'd rather do the opposite.
I'd rather just be exactly who I am and
call it for what it is. Because when I
do good or when I
sign a deal like today, I want to
celebrate it and call it for what it is.
[snorts]
But, when I don't do my job, the job
that I was called to do, let's just
handle it. You know what I mean? I'm not
scared of it. I'm not scared of
controversy. I'm not scared of conflict.
I'm not scared of failing because
football isn't what's most important to
me. My my faith in Jesus and where I'm
going after this life is far more
important than any game of football. So,
I'm not scared to admit that I missed a
block because that doesn't define me. Um
but
if we call it for what it is, it was a
big deal and it was really hard. And I
just felt like in that moment if my kid
my future kid is watching me, I think
about that all the time or my wife is
watching me, I would rather them look at
me and be a man and say, "I can own my
mistakes and I can move forward and I
can do my job the best I can and accept
it for what it is rather than being
someone that makes excuses." I think
excuses are the worst. So, it was tough
and in moments like that, you you look
at yourself in the mirror and say, "What
the heck? Like this isn't what I thought
was I had planned for this season." But,
you have two choices like I've been
saying all morning and I made the choice
to bite down and flush it and say, "It's
one block. It's one play. Could have
happened to anybody. Let's move forward.
Let's have a great rest of the season."
And you saw how I played the rest of the
year. You saw how we came together as an
off-
fensive line and
I think I just got to give credit to all
the people that believed in me and gave
me a shot moving forward from that. What
was it like in the game like the opener?
What was that that like? Super cool,
Hobbs. Um I felt like I was on that
little patch of grass avoiding dog poop
8 days prior and then I was at the dog
pound and looking at Myles Garrett
across from me. So, I said, "Man, this
is a pretty big switch." Um
but that's what I was This is what I've
been born to do. This is the sport that
I love and I felt right back at home.
This is a sport I've been doing ever
since I was 6 years old and as no matter
what, if you take 6 months off or 2
months or you go through OTAs or you
don't, when you put those pads back on,
you
represent the Cincinnati Bengals, and if
God God willing, I get to play year
nine, then great. But, I'd hate to get
to year eight or year nine and and not
make it to 10. So,
if this is my last stop, that'd be a
heck of a way to to end my career.
Hopefully, we play here for three or
four more years, and Cincinnati can be
the place that I call home. Talked
earlier about uh, you know, celebrating
days like this at the end of the season.
You know, you said how much you love
Cincinnati. You have Ruby Soto. How do
you celebrate a day like this?
>> right? We're flying back to Tampa. We
got to get our dog. We were in Colorado
on a I had a a men's conference I was
speaking at, and I was seeing family.
So, it just got It wasn't something that
we expected to get done. I didn't think,
anyways. So, the fact that we got it
done was a little unexpected. We're on
the road, so we got to get home. I'm
going to celebrate with my wife and my
dog. Um, this is my way to celebrate.
Celebrate with you guys. Giving Obi a
hug. Talking to Zac. Talking to Scott
Peters. Uh, staying at the hotel last
night. The Bengals have rolled out the
red carpet. Man, they've, you know, we
had snacks waiting on us, and um, we're
pretty easy-going people, but they've
taken great care of us, made us feel
really special. And truly, the way we
celebrate is go win a Super Bowl, bro.
You know what I mean? Not going to throw
a big party. Not going to stay up too
late. I I like to be in bed by 8:00 p.m.
tonight, and get back to working out
tomorrow, and and the world keeps going.
You know, you scared uh, a lot of fans
when you bought a house in Kansas City.
>> Dude, what was up with that? Did it
scare you? Did you hear that? Not
necessarily. I just didn't know if you
saw that reaction to you guys
Fans at home No, I don't see anything.
So, just so fans know, and you guys
know, I'm on no social. So, if you see a
post, it's not me. But,
>> work. What? Way to work. Yeah, exactly.
[laughter]
I like to stay off the grid, right? Life
is like this. But, my wife is on all
social media, so she updates me, and
she's like, man, fans are in an uproar.
We bought a house in Kansas. They don't
think we're coming back. And if I would
have known fans took that the wrong way,
I would not have done it. But, I mean, I
I guess they expect me I had to buy a
house in Cincinnati, but um, no, that
had nothing to do with anything, guys.
My wife's family's from there. Um,
that's where we're going to start going
for off-season, and that's where we're
going to spend some time to get closer
to family, but um, hopefully, all the
fans that had given up hope when we
bought a house in Kansas are regaining
some faith today.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, thank you guys all for being here.
Yeah, Who Dey. God bless. Go Bengals.
>> [music]
[music]